<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>terraform on Dominik Rys</title>
    <link>https://dominikrys.com/tags/terraform/</link>
    <description>Recent content in terraform on Dominik Rys</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://dominikrys.com/android-chrome-512x512.png</url>
      <link>https://dominikrys.com/android-chrome-512x512.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 10:38:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dominikrys.com/tags/terraform/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>&#39;HashiCorp Certified: Terraform Associate&#39; Course Review</title>
      <link>https://dominikrys.com/posts/terraform-course-review-zealvora/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 10:38:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominikrys.com/posts/terraform-course-review-zealvora/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently been working with Terraform a lot at work. However, I was never taught properly how it works. I jumped straight into the code and figured things out, which wasn&amp;rsquo;t particularly difficult. Nevertheless, I was curious as to what I was missing and how I could set Terraform up myself in a new project. Therefore, I looked at how I could learn Terraform on my own.
After some initial looking around, I found Zeal Vora&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;HashiCorp Certified: Terraform Associate&amp;rsquo; course on Udemy to be well-regarded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caveats to Creating Datadog Log Metrics in Terraform</title>
      <link>https://dominikrys.com/posts/datadog-log-metrics-terraform/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 09:52:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominikrys.com/posts/datadog-log-metrics-terraform/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I give an overview of how to create Datadog Log Metrics in Terraform. Having had done this recently, I encountered a couple of caveats that warranted documenting. Hopefully it will help others that encountered similar issues.
This post assumes that you have a basic configuration for Datadog in Terraform already. If you don&amp;rsquo;t, Datadog&amp;rsquo;s post on managing Datadog with Terraform is a good starting point.
Datadog Terraform Resources There are three Terraform resources that you can use to configure log metrics in Datadog:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
