<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on Dominik Rys</title>
        <link>https://dominikrys.com/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on Dominik Rys</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-GB</language>
        <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 15:16:16 +0100</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://dominikrys.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>My First Blog Post</title>
            <link>https://dominikrys.com/posts/2020/08/my-first-blog-post/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 15:16:16 +0100</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://dominikrys.com/posts/2020/08/my-first-blog-post/</guid>
            <description>Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Dom. Welcome to my first blog post!
My main objective for this blog is to start documenting my work more. Having had completed some small side projects and interning at some companies, I found that it was difficult to remember certain quirks and details of my past work. Starting a blog and having this knowledge elegantly formatted and stored away will hopefully remedy this issue.
As for the tech stack I used to set up this blog, it&amp;rsquo;s quite straightforward.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hi, I&rsquo;m Dom. Welcome to my first blog post!</p>
<p>My main objective for this blog is to start documenting my work more. Having had completed some small side projects and interning at some companies, I found that it was difficult to remember certain quirks and details of my past work. Starting a blog and having this knowledge elegantly formatted and stored away will hopefully remedy this issue.</p>
<p>As for the tech stack I used to set up this blog, it&rsquo;s quite straightforward. <a href="https://gohugo.io/">Hugo</a> is the static site generator responsible for most of the heavy work, allowing me to write this blog post simply in Markdown. The site is then hosted on GitHub Pages (with <a href="https://github.blog/2009-12-29-bypassing-jekyll-on-github-pages/">Jekyll bypassed</a>).</p>
<p>Alternative static site generators I&rsquo;ve also considered are <a href="https://www.gatsbyjs.org/">Gatsby</a> and <a href="https://jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll</a>:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Gatsby is arguably a more popular solution, however supposedly <a href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/gatsby-vs-hugo-a-detailed-comparison-e78d94f640fc/">requires knowledge of React</a>. I was looking for an easily maintainable solution which &ldquo;just works&rdquo;, so Hugo seemed like a winner.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Jekyll is used by default on GitHub pages so it felt like the more natural choice. I&rsquo;ve tried to set it up in the past to have a GitHub pages page redirect to another site (which I quickly found I don&rsquo;t need Jekyll for), but the set-up process was horrible. I&rsquo;ve tried it on Windows and Linux, and ran into lots of issues with it requiring certain Ruby versions and specific environment settings. Hugo worked out of the box.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>I got the final nudge to get to work with this blog after reading the book <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/18290401-show-your-work">Show Your Work</a> by Austin Kleon. I highly recommend it as it&rsquo;s super short and packed with plenty of useful advice.</p>
<p>I hope you find the content on this blog useful!</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
