<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Networking on Dominik Rys</title>
    <link>https://dominikrys.com/tags/networking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Networking on Dominik Rys</description>
    <image>
      <title>Dominik Rys</title>
      <url>https://dominikrys.com/android-chrome-512x512.png</url>
      <link>https://dominikrys.com/android-chrome-512x512.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.140.2</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 15:36:55 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://dominikrys.com/tags/networking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Executing Stream Cipher Attacks on IP Packets</title>
      <link>https://dominikrys.com/posts/stream-cipher-attacks-on-ip/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 15:36:55 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dominikrys.com/posts/stream-cipher-attacks-on-ip/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For part of my bachelor&amp;rsquo;s dissertation, I implemented and executed a bit-flipping attack on encrypted IP packets in LTE networks. The attack was first documented by David Rupprecht et al. in their academic paper &lt;a href=&#34;https://alter-attack.net/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Breaking LTE on Layer Two&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The attack is possible due to a specification flaw in LTE standards, where IP packets are &lt;strong&gt;not integrity protected&lt;/strong&gt;. Therefore, a man-in-the-middle (MITM) attacker can modify the packets and the receiver will decrypt them successfully since it can&amp;rsquo;t verify the authenticity of the data. This kind of attack is not specific to LTE networks, however, and can be executed in different environments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Disable UDP Checksum Validation in Linux</title>
      <link>https://dominikrys.com/posts/disable-udp-checksum-validation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 12:37:22 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dominikrys.com/posts/disable-udp-checksum-validation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently needed to disable the validation of UDP checksums of incoming packets on a Linux machine for a security project. To my surprise, there weren&amp;rsquo;t any satisfactory solutions that I could easily find online related to this. The top Google results suggest &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linuxquestions.org/questions/linux-networking-3/help-needed-disabling-tcp-udp-checksum-offloading-in-debian-880233/&#34;&gt;disabling checksum offloading&lt;/a&gt;, which doesn&amp;rsquo;t disable checksum validation. Another result mentions &lt;a href=&#34;https://linux-tips.com/t/how-to-disable-udp-checksum-control-in-kernel/362&#34;&gt;a solution from within application source code&lt;/a&gt;, which you may not have access to or be able to modify.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Transparently Proxy IP Packets With Spoofed Destinations</title>
      <link>https://dominikrys.com/posts/transparently-proxy-spoofed-ip/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 10:44:53 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dominikrys.com/posts/transparently-proxy-spoofed-ip/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve recently worked on a security project which required me to transparently proxy IP packets that have had their destination IPs spoofed. By this, I mean that the destination IP in an IP packet is &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; the IP of the destination which a DNS request would correctly resolve. For example, this could be due to a DNS query being spoofed and sending an IP address of another destination in reply. The diagram above shows what we want to achieve.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
