<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Dominik Rys</title>
    <link>https://dominikrys.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Dominik Rys</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 10:34:48 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dominikrys.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Debug srsLTE</title>
      <link>https://dominikrys.com/blog/how-to-debug-srslte/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 10:34:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominikrys.com/blog/how-to-debug-srslte/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently been working extensively with srsLTE for my university dissertation. So far, the greatest difficulty has been debugging the software. In this short post, I will describe various ways I found that srsLTE can be debugged, and any pitfalls that come with them.
I&amp;rsquo;ll assume you know how to debug ordinary C/C++ programs (I&amp;rsquo;ll patiently wait here if you need to have a look into that).
Compiling srsLTE in debug mode Your first attempt at debugging may have been to compile with the Debug CMake flag, and then executing the binaries using GDB or another debugger:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up a TLS-Secured Monitoring Solution in Docker using InfluxDB, Grafana and Traefik</title>
      <link>https://dominikrys.com/blog/setting-up-tls-secured-monitoring-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 12:51:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominikrys.com/blog/setting-up-tls-secured-monitoring-docker/</guid>
      <description>Motivation During my last internship, I&amp;rsquo;ve been tasked with designing and deploying infrastructure for monitoring a cluster of machines that were used for performance testing. I wrote a blog post detailing high-level choices about it which you can check out here. The post also includes justifications for why I chose to deploy everything in Docker, and why I chose to work with Grafana and InfluxDB as the front-end and time-series database, respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring Corda Nodes Using Grafana, InfluxDB, and Telegraf</title>
      <link>https://dominikrys.com/blog/monitoring-corda-nodes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 16:52:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominikrys.com/blog/monitoring-corda-nodes/</guid>
      <description>This post is also hosted on the Corda Blog. The main goal behind this post was to provide an easily accessible high-level overview on monitoring Corda nodes. It also showcases part of what I&amp;rsquo;ve done during my summer internship at R3.
 Intro Here at R3, we have a cluster of Corda nodes that we use for performance testing. We have developed a performance testing suite that enables us to establish baseline numbers, quantify improvements from new features, and identify regressions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compiling a C&#43;&#43; CHIP-8 Emulator to WebAssembly</title>
      <link>https://dominikrys.com/blog/compiling-chip8-to-wasm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 16:55:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominikrys.com/blog/compiling-chip8-to-wasm/</guid>
      <description>Intro A couple of months ago I wrote a CHIP-8 emulator in C++17, as I wanted to learn about emulation and expand my C++ knowledge outside of work. In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll explain how I went about compiling the emulator which was designed to run natively, to also run on the web using the magic of WebAssembly. You can try out the result here.
My main motivation for getting the emulator working on the web was that in its current state, it took some effort to get it up and running.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
