<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>linux on Dominik Rys</title>
    <link>https://dominikrys.com/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in linux on Dominik Rys</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 12:37:22 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dominikrys.com/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Disable UDP Checksum Checking in Linux</title>
      <link>https://dominikrys.com/posts/2021/05/how-to-disable-udp-checksum-checking-in-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 12:37:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominikrys.com/posts/2021/05/how-to-disable-udp-checksum-checking-in-linux/</guid>
      <description>I recently needed to disable the checking of UDP checksums of incoming packets on a Linux machine for a security project. To my surprise, there weren&amp;rsquo;t any satisfactory solutions that I could easily find online related to this. The top results also suggested disabling checksum offloading, which doesn&amp;rsquo;t disable checksum checking. In the end, I managed to figure this problem out and found that it&amp;rsquo;s possible without recompiling the kernel. In this short post, I&amp;rsquo;ll describe how to set up a Linux machine to ignore UDP checksums in received packets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Transparently Proxy IP Packets With Spoofed Destinations</title>
      <link>https://dominikrys.com/posts/2021/04/how-to-transparently-proxy-ip-packets-with-spoofed-destinations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 10:44:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dominikrys.com/posts/2021/04/how-to-transparently-proxy-ip-packets-with-spoofed-destinations/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently worked on a security project which required me to transparently/interceptingly (if that&amp;rsquo;s a word) proxy IP packets that have had their destination IPs spoofed. By this, I mean that the destination IP in an IP packet is not the IP of the destination which a DNS request would correctly resolve. For example, this could be due to a DNS query being spoofed and sending an IP address of another destination in reply.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
